<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>المقالات والملاحظات</title>
    <link>https://maz12211.github.io/notes-and-blogs/</link>
    <description>موقع أدون فيه ما أعرفه عن أدوات\الأدوات التي استخدمتها لتعديل اللعبة.</description>
    <language>ar</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>EasyRPG Notes</title>
      <link>https://maz12211.github.io/notes-and-blogs/posts/EasyRPG-Notes.html</link>
      <description>Last major page update: 6/1/2024
Tested on v0.8
Notes taken during translating/playtesting in an RTL language (in this case Arabic):
You're expected to know EasyRPG's translation tool before reading this.
General info
Putting English text in the middle of an Arabic sentence (or word) anywhere flips the said English text example: CSE instead of ESC, elppa instead of apple, so they have to be reversed.
Item/Weapon/Armor/Magic Descriptions
Meaning you have to change the order of words from left-to-right because EasyRPG can't render text from Right-To-Left (except message boxes)

Converting the sentence doesn't work out for RPGM.

Message boxes (when characters speak)
I'm able to type Arabic normally without reversing anything (!مرحى)
Code language for the meta.ini
I didn't playtest this with others a lot, but I'll assume it's correct because it makes sense (and because I got no complaints). the code language for Arabic translations have to be ar as putting for example ar-IQ means only poeple living in Iraq can play it (or I guess only people with their system local set to Arabic Iraq)

Issues (so far)
RPG_RT.ldb.common texts don't apply for some reason (they're still in English). So far this only happened in LISA The First

Game's font didn't change until I renamed the `Font.ttf` to `Font2.ttf` in the Font folder (shouldn't the former work too?) So far this only happened in LISA The First.</description>
      <pubDate>2024/6/1</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maz12211.github.io/notes-and-blogs/posts/EasyRPG-Notes.html</guid>
    </item>
    <!--Add more items here-->
  </channel>
</rss>